Ravin Vasudev

Software Development Engineer

Fredericton, NB 506-440-9754 ravinvasudev@gmail.com

Software engineer with 12 years of robust experience in software design and development, looking for a long-term committed career working with a team of smart and motivated people, where I can experience new technologies, enrich my career, and add value for users and business.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks

Java, Spring, Spring Boot, JAX-RS (REST web services), Jersey, Spring Rest API, Spring Data Repositories, Spring MVC, JAX-WS (SOAP web services), Spring Security, SQL, JPA, JUnit5, Mockito, PowerMockito

Tools

IntelliJ, Maven, GIT, GitHub, BitBucket, JIRA, Jenkins, Crucible, FishEye, Postman, SOAP UI, Docker, IBM RTC

Concepts

Agile Software Development, Microservices Architecture, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Design Patterns, Cloud Platforms, High Availability & Scaling, Caching

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Design Engineer

July 2019 - Present

Siemens Canada Limited, Canada

- Working on Smart Grid Infrastructure solution build on top of Siemens EIP platform.
- Designing Event Template feature to reduce events configuration by 80%. It will significantly enhance
 events creation process and provide the end customer with extensibility and usability.

Solutions Architect

August 2014 - February 2019

Etisalat Software Solutions Pvt Ltd, Dubai

- Decoupled Etisalat's complex monolithic architecture into multiple loosely coupled services. It allows
 clients to integrate with specific services to support their business scenarios, bringing down the time
 investment and integration complexities.
- Designed and developed REST interfaces integrated by multiple frontends (web portal, self care kiosk, business centers etc.) to enable customers to renew mobile account registration with convenience.
- Developed REST service integrated by company-wide systems to send SMS and Email notifications to customers. It was designed to handle sending 100 thousand messages a day and included traceability and reporting features to make it easier for contact center employees to address customers queries.
- Designed and developed OTP service integrated by multiple clients to authenticate user transaction.
- Developed a solution to log various customer interactions from multiple channels and built a management system for contact center to retrieve historical view to address customer queries. This significantly improved the customers' complaint resolution time.
- Revamped legacy SMS, USSD and IVR administration web portal to reduce service configuration time from 30 to 10 minutes and enhanced performance, convenience and usability.

• Received "Etisalat Hero" award twice for exemplary performance.

Senior Solution Integrator

February 2012 - July 2014

Ericsson India Global Services Pvt Ltd, India

- Integrated Ericsson's revenue driven PrePaid Charging System with AT&T Billing System to bring subscriber billing, administration and management features to AT&T Mobility (ATTM) platform.
- Added hybrid features to ATTM platform that provide subscribers with the flexibility to manage mobile usage, payment methods and enabled to use postpay & prepay modes on the same account.
- Wrote multiple adapters for Amdocs Cramer system to process network and inventory data.

Senior Software Engineer

March 2009 - February 2012

Digivision Entertainment Pvt Ltd, India

- Built consumer services for IPTV system like Facebook, Gmail, Twitter and other services.
- Enhanced user experience by developing multi-tap functionality and search feature on IPTV.
- Reduced bandwidth consumption by upto 80% by implementing multicast-shut feature when broadcast is not in use.

Software Engineer

April 2007 - March 2009

Aithent Technologies Pvt Ltd, India

- Developed application for insurance agents to take online courses.
- Worked on an aggregator platform for B2B customers to provide licensing information.
- Developed a wiki-based portal for knowledge sharing within the company.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Information Technology

Beant College of Engineering & Technology, Gurdaspur

Diploma in Computer Engineering

Thapar Polytechnic, Patiala